Dorothy Liebes
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Dorothy Liebes papers
circa 1850-1973 (bulk 1922-1970)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Liebes, Dorothy
21.4 linear feet
The papers of weaver, textile designer, and businesswoman Dorothy Liebes are dated circa 1850-1973 (bulk 1922-1970), and comprise 21.4 linear feet. Biographical information, subject files, correspondence, writings, artwork, financial records, scrapbooks, textile samples, printed material, sound recordings, and photographs document Liebes' career and personal life. Her second husband, Associated Press Reporter Relman "Pat" Morin, is also represented in the collection, although to a much lesser extent.
Provenance
Gift of the Estate of Dorothy Liebes through Relman Morin (widower), 1972, and Ralph Higbee, 1973-1974.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Weaver, textile designer, and businesswoman Dorothy Wright Liebes was known for distinctive textiles featuring bold color combinations and unusual textures achieved through the use of materials such as glass rods, sequins, bamboo, grass, leather, ribbon, wire, and ticker tape.
Born Dorothy Wright in Santa Rosa, California, she was the daughter of chemistry professor Frederick L. Wright and teacher Bessie Calderwood Wright. She studied art, education, and anthropology at San Jose State Teachers College and the University of California, Berkeley. During her college years, a teacher encouraged her to experiment with weaving and textile design since many of her paintings resembled textiles.
Liebes was a teacher for several years before deciding to pursue a career in textile design. She then studied weaving at Hull House in Chicago and traveled to France, Italy, Guatemala, and Mexico to learn the traditional weaving forms of those cultures. Upon her return to the United States, Liebes opened her first studio for weaving and textile design in San Francisco; Dorothy Liebes Design, Inc. was established in 1934, and eventually employed a staff of weavers.
Her first client in the industry was Goodall-Sanford Mills, with whom she worked as a consultant for more than a decade. As her client base expanded she decided to open a New York studio and maintained both studios until 1948 when she closed her San Francisco operation and relocated to New York City.
Liebes became a color and design consultant to corporations such as DuPont, Dow, and Bigelow-Sanford and tested and promoted newly developed synthetic fibers. She advised textile chemists in the development of fibers that were versatile enough to produce many different textures, and worked with engineers and technicians to develop new machines that could reproduce the irregularities of hand-loomed fabrics. Liebes became a sought-after speaker by textile industry and consumer groups, and sometimes taught workshops on color and design.
Her commissions included the United Nations Delegates Dining Room, the Persian Room at the Plaza Hotel and the King of Saudi Arabia's traveling royal throne room. Between 1937 and 1970, Liebes participated in more than thirty solo and group exhibitions at the San Francisco Museum of Art, Museum of Modern Art, de Young Museum, Cranbrook Museum, Detroit Institute of Art, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Museum of Contemporary Crafts, and other venues. She received prizes and awards from institutions and corporations such as Lord and Taylor, Neiman-Marcus, the Paris Exposition, the American Institute of Decorators, the American Institute of Architects and the Architectural League. She was also awarded the Elsie de Wolfe Award and an honorary degree from Mills College in 1948.
Liebes' other notable activities included her work as Director of Decorative Arts for the 1939 San Francisco World's Fair, and as organizer and director of "Arts and Skills," a Red Cross occupational therapy project that included training in weaving for soldiers injured in World War II. In the 1950s, she worked with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, journeying though the southwest to study Indian schools and show weaver tribes that horizontal looms were more advantageous than vertical ones.
Liebes was married to businessman Leon Liebes from 1928 until their divorce in 1940, and continued to use the name Liebes for the remainder of her life. In 1948, she married Pulitzer prize winning Associated Press special correspondent Relman "Pat" Morin.
During the last year of her life, Dorothy Liebes was semi-retired due to a heart ailment. She died in New York City on 10 September 1972.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of weaver, textile designer, and businesswoman Dorothy Liebes are dated circa 1850-1973 (bulk 1922-1970), and comprise 21.4 linear feet. Biographical information, subject files, correspondence, writings, artwork, financial records, scrapbooks, textile samples, printed material, sound recordings, and photographs document Liebes' career and personal life. Her second husband, Associated Press Reporter Relman "Pat" Morin, is also represented in the collection, although to a much lesser extent.
Biographical material consists of awards, biographical notes, membership and identification cards, passports, and a will. Dorothy Liebes' correspondence documents her personal life and career, including the operation of her studios in San Francisco and New York City.
Subject files contain correspondence, printed material, photographs, and miscellaneous items in varying combinations. They relate to businesses, organizations, individuals, and topics of interest to Liebes.
Writings by Dorothy Liebes include notes, drafts, and manuscripts of published and unpublished writings. Artwork by Dorothy Liebes consists of designs, feather weavings, a small hooked composition, and tapestry samples. Financial records are comprised of financial summaries, investment statements, and personal and business tax returns. Thirty-three bound scrapbook volumes contain printed and publicity materials, photographs, and a small number of documents relating to Dorothy Liebes' professional achievements.
Samples consist primarily of textile swatches designed by Dorothy Liebes and printed material includes articles, exhibition catalogs, press releases, and reproductions about or mentioning Dorothy Liebes and her work, as well as reproductions of artwork.
Also found are calendars, a transcript of a 1945 interview with Liebes on Nancy Craig's radio show "Woman of Tomorrow" and a circa 1956 sound recording on 5" magnetic tape from the Milwaukee Journal Radio Station.
Photographs are of artwork (not by Liebes), people, including Liebes, Relman "Pat" Morin, and Frank Lloyd Wright, places and textiles.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Morin, Relman, 1907-1973
Subjects-Topical:
Textile design -- New York (State) -- New York; Women textile designers -- New York (State) -- New York; Weavers -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Sound recordings; Scrapbooks; Works of art
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1934-1970 (Box 1, OV 22; 6 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1922-1973 (Boxes 1-3; 2.4 linear ft.)
Series 3: Subject Files, 1896-1971 (Boxes 3-10, 19; 7.2 linear ft.)
Series 4: Writings, 1920-1969 (Boxes 10-11; 1.25 linear ft.)
Series 5: Artwork, 1938-1963 (Boxes 11, 19, OV 22; 0.35 linear ft.)
Series 6: Financial Records, 1947-1968 (Box 12; 0.25 linear ft.)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1933-1970 (Box 20, BV 24-56; 3.7 linear ft.)
Series 8: Samples, circa 1850-1855, circa 1930s-circa 1970 (Boxes 12-14, 20; 2.1 linear ft.)
Series 9: Calendars and Interviews, 1945-1971 (Boxes 14-15; 1.45 linear ft.)
Series 10: Printed Material, 1897-1970 (Boxes 15-16, 20-21, OV 23; 1.05 linear ft.)
Series 11: Photographs, 1897-1970 (Boxes 16-18, 21, BV 57; 1.5 linear ft.)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Information, 1934-1970, Series 1:; (Box 1, OV 22; 6 folders)
  - Awards, 1938-1969, (2 folders; see also OV 22) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Notes (Dorothy Liebes), 1954-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership and Identification Cards, 1934-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Passports, 1954, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Will, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards, 1937-1965 (Box OV 22)
- Correspondence, 1922-1973, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-3; 2.4 linear ft.)
  This series contains a combination of business and personal correspondence. Series 3: Subject Files, also contains large amounts of correspondence and there is substantial overlap between the two series. In addition, Series 7: Scrapbooks, includes a small number of letters and other documents.
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1922-1960, (25 folders) (Box 1, Folder 6-30)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1968, (22 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-22)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1973, undated, (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 23-30)
- Subject Files, 1896-1971, Series 3:; (Boxes 3-10, 19; 7.2 linear ft.)
  Subject files may contain correspondence, printed material, photographs, and miscellaneous records in various combinations. Subjects include corporations, organizations, individuals, topics of interest to Liebes, and miscellaneous categories. Folder titles are often those supplied by Liebes.
  Subject files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Alcan Aluminum Corporation, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1947 Conference, "The Artist in Contemporary American Society," 1945-1948, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - American Crafts Council, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - American Craftsmen's Cooperative Council, Inc., 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - American Craftsmen's Council, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - American Craftsmen's Council, First World Congress of Craftsmen, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - American Craftsmen's Educational Council, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - American Women's Voluntary Services, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Architectural Forum, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Architecture Schools, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1956-1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Artists, 1945-1958, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
  - Artists, Designs, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Artists, Northern California, 1943-1947 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Artists, Out of State, 1943-1947 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Artists, Southern California, 1945-1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "Arts and Skills" (American Red Cross), 1943-1952, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 49-51)
  - Azukas, Albert, 1950-1956 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Company, Inc., Correspondence, 1957-1971, (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
  - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Company, Inc., June Market, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Company, Inc., Printed Material, 1964-1965, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Company, Inc., Western Trip, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Black Mountain College, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Book Inquiries, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Brandt, Mary, Lecture Committee, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Brandt, Mary, Lectures at Parsons School of Design, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Brandt, Mary, Memorial Fund, 1962-1963, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Buxton, Edward, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Calder, Sandy [Alexander], 1957 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Calypsocraft, Inc. (Edward Fields), Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Calypsocraft, Inc. (Edward Fields), Expenses, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Calypsocraft, Inc. (Edward Fields), Expenses and Packing Lists, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Challis, Lucy, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Christmas, Lists and Names, 1935-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Clemson University 1969," 1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Clothing, "Suggestions, Bills, Inventory," 1939-1945 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Columbia Mills, 1944-1958 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Contemporary Weaving of Other Countries, 1959-1960, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 28-29)
  - Contracts, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1954-1963, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Crawford, M.D.C., 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Cruise, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Designs Received/Returned/Purchased, 1943-1947, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - Dobby Loom, 1944-1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Dobeckmun Co., 1946-1967, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
  - Dow Chemical, Correspondence, 1959-1961, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 40-42)
  - Dow Chemical, Lurex Division, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Dow Chemical, Lurex Division, London, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Dow Chemical, Packing Lists, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Draper, Dorothy (Good Housekeeping), 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Dupont, Correspondence, 1943-1971, (18 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-18)
  - Dupont, Expenses, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Dupont, Fabric Sales, Fabrite and Tontine (Price/Edwards/Ferris), 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Dupont, Fabric Sales, Packing Lists, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Dupont, January Market (1960), 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Dupont, January Market (1962), 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dupont, June Market (1962), 1962, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
  - Dupont, January Market (1963), Upholstery, Orlon, and Drapery Project, 1962-1963, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
  - Dupont, January Market, June Market (1963), 1962-1963, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Dupont, January Market, June Market (1964), 1964, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Dupont, January Market, June Market (1965), 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dupont, January Market, June Market (1966), 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Dupont, January Market (1967), 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dupont, June Market (1967), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Dupont, Knit Products (Dr. Robert Saunders), 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dupont, Monthly Reports, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dupont, "Nylon Rug Designs" (Smithsonian Traveling Exhibition), 1956-1962 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dupont, Orlon Blanket (Beacon Manufacturing Co.), 1961 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Dupont, Pacific Northwest Arts and Crafts Fair, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Dupont, Publicity, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Dupont, Rugs, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dupont, Rugs, Nylon-Wool (Werner Cohen), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Dupont, Upholstery and Drapery, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Eagle-Ottawa Leather Co., 1958-1960 (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Erdman, Pardee, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Fairtex, Correspondence, 1963-1965, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
  - Fairtex, Correspondence, 1965-1968, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Fairtex, Detroit Show (1966), 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fairtex, Mint Museum Fabric, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fairtex, Packing Lists, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fairtex, Samples, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Fairtex, "Styling Color Folder," 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Family, Morin, Relman "Pat" (see Morin, Relman "Pat") (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Family, Nieces and Nephews, 1945-1966, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Family, Wood, Mildred "Tid" Wright, Ralph, and Peter, 1944-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Family, Wright, Frederick and Bessie Calderwood, 1896-circa 1957, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - Family, Wright, Frederick L., 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Family, Wright, William F., 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fan Mail, 1944-1946, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - Fields, Edward, 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
  - Fischer, Eva, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Foreign Mails," 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Forstmann Woolen Company, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Furnishing Studio Home in Washington, D.C.," 1948 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Golden Gate Exposition, "Case History," 1945-1948, (see also Box 19) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Golden Gate Exposition, Catalogues and Sales, 1939, (see also Box 19) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Golden Gate Exposition, Correspondence, 1937-1940, (2 folders; see also Box 19) (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Goodall Fabrics, Correspondence, 1942-1953, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
  - Goodall Fabrics, "Leather Weave," 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Goodall Fabrics, Mailing Lists for Announcements, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gracie and Sons, Inc. (wallpaper), 1957-1964 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Grimm, Peter, 1941-1947 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Hartford Rayon Company, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - India Trip, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Indian Job," 1950-1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Indian School, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Indian Textiles, 1943-1953, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Indian Trips (René D'Harnoncourt), 1942-1943, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Institute of International Education, National Screening Committee, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Insurance, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Interesting Personal Letters," 1939-1947, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Inventory (business), 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Inventory (personal), 1937-1946 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Israel, 1950-1954, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Jantzen Mills, 1947-1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Japan, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Kenwood Mills, Blanket Orders, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Kenwood Mills, Blanket Publicity, 1953, (see: Box 19) (Box 8)
  - Kenwood Mills, Correspondence, 1950-1951, (5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-20)
  - Kenwood Mills, "Current Problems," 1951 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Kuhn, Harold A. (C.P.A.), 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Lawyer, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Library Inventory, 1946, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Liebes, Leon (first husband), 1935-1946 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Lyons Storage Co., 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Matson vs. Liebes, 1946-1948 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Mills College, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Morin, Relman "Pat" (second husband), 1947-1959, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 30-34)
  - Museum of Contemporary Crafts (Dorothy Liebes Retrospective Exhibition), 1970 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1944-1970 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Museums, General, 1959-1970 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Myers, Howard, 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, 1956-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Navajo Rug Project, 1959-1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - New York, Trip (Oct.-Jan.), 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - New York, Unfinished Business, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Orders, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Orders Completed, 1958-1967, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Parsons School of Design, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Penco Fabrics, Inc., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Pheby, Louise S. (Estate of), 1955-1961, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - "Pre-Fab Inquiries," 1962 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Private Papers," 1929-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Promotion, 1950-1960, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 14-18)
  - Richards, Helen, 1942-1955, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1954-1967 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Samples Returned, 1956, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - San Francisco Bay Exposition, 1939-1943 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - San Francisco International Market Center, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Scranton Lace Co., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Simmons Co., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Spring Mills, Inc., Contracts, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Spring Mills, Inc., Correspondence, 1963-1966, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Spring Mills, Inc., Reports, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Studio, Correspondence, 1945-1955, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 30-35)
  - Studio, Letters to Personnel, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Studio Trouble – Ruth and Al," 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Taipale, Martta (tapestries), 1946-1961, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
  - Tapestry, American (20th century), 1959-1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Tapestry, English, 1956-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tapestry, French, 1948-1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Tapestry, General, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Tapestry, Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Tapestry, Scandinavian, 1958-1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Tax Suit, 1948-1957 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Teaching (notes, Woman's Day article), 1944-1959, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Travel, 1947-1963, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Unifinished Business," 1936-1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - U.S.A. at the Triennale, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - U. S. Department of State, Conference on International Relations in the Field of Art, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - United Wallpaper, Inc., 1945-1956, (see also: Box 19) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - University of California, Berkeley, 1933, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - University of Kansas, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Upholstery Leather Group, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Van Buren, William M., 1941-1946 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Weavers and Weaving, 1946-1951, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 23-25)
  - Weaving Verse, 1954, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Women Architects, 1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd and Olgivanna, 1947-1969 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Golden Gate Exposition, 1938, (see also Box 7) (Box 19 (sol))
  - Kenwood Mills, Blanket Publicity, 1953 (Box 19 (sol))
  - United Wallpaper, Inc. (Sample Book, "Weaves from exclusive hand-loomed originals by Dorothy Liebes,") undated, (see also Box 10) (Box 19 (sol))
- Writings, 1920-1969, Series 4:; (Boxes 10-11; 1.25 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  4.1: Writings By Dorothy Liebes, 1920-1965
  4.2: Writings by Other Authors, 1944-1969
  - Writings By Dorothy Liebes, 1920-1965, 4.1:
    This subseries includes notes, drafts, and manuscripts of published and unpublished articles and short writings. Also found here are notes, drafts and the manuscript for an unpublished autobiography, as well as an outline, notes and partial draft of an unpublished book, "Design and Weave." There are drafts, text and bibliographical material for an Encyclopedia Britannica entry on tapestry, as well as notes relating to speeches and writings.
    - Address Books, undated, (4 volumes; 2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
    - Articles and Short Writings, 1946-1964, undated, (4 volumes; 2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 31-32)
    - Book, Autobiography Manuscript, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 33-34)
    - Book, Authobiography Notes and Drafts, undated, (4 folders) (Box 10, Folder 35-38)
    - Book, Autobiography Outline, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Book, "Design and Weave," undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Entry on Tapestry, circa 1959, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Lists, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Notes, undated, (3 folders and 4x6 card file) (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
    - Speeches, 1946-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    - Student Paper (?) by Dorothy K. Wright, "Modern Materials" (with samples), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Writings by Other Authors, 1944-1969, 4.2:
    This subseries includes articles about Liebes from the City Art Museum, St. Louis and other unsigned sources; articles on various topics by people such as Edith Grimm, Vesta Schaffer and Iovanna Lloyd Wright; a report by Dorothy Ducas; and speeches by people such as L. R. Blackhurst, Jr., W. G. Constable, Charles Daly, Boris Kroll, Sarah Tomerlin Lee, Sara Little, George Romeny, Edward Wormley, and David L.Yunich.
    - Articles about Dorothy Liebes, 1945-circa 1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Articles on Various Topics, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Poem (Jack James), undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Report, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 13)